Guide to the James Welch Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1889-2000; Series I; 13.35; (32 boxes)
  - POETRY
    - Collections
      - Master proof, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations (World Pub. Co. ed.)
      - [Master] proof, photocopy, [1971?] (Box 23, Folder 193)
      - Galley proof (Harper & Row ed.)
      - Page proofs (Harper & Row ed.), 1975 (Box 23, Folder 194)
      - Blues (Harper & Row ed.), 1975 (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - Individual Poems
      - "Across to the Peloponnese", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 196)
      - "Airplane, Cold Summer Nights", 1968 May, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 197)
      - "All Mistakes Made on a Typewriter", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 198)
      - "Alley Behind Eddie's" (Box 23, Folder 199)
      - "Almost a Visit", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 200)
      - "And the Hummingbirds Shall Hover at Her Breasts", [ca. 1966] (Box 23, Folder 201)
      - "And Tell Your Friends" (Box 23, Folder 202)
      - "Argument for Lures", 1968 Jul 18 (Box 23, Folder 203)
      - "Arizona Highways", 1971 (Box 23, Folder 204)
      - "Ars Poetica", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 205)
      - "Aunt Effie", [1968] (Box 23, Folder 206)
      - "Autumnal", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 207)
      - "Barter for Bride", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 208)
      - "Bear Paw Fall", [1968-1969] (Box 23, Folder 209)
      - "Before Breakup on the Chena", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - "Birth on Range 22", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - "Birthday in Saronis", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 212)
      - "Blackbirds Dropping", [ca. 1966] (Box 23, Folder 213)
      - "Blackfeet, Blood and Plegan Hunters", 1967 (Box 23, Folder 214)
      - "Blowing", [ca. 1966] (Box 23, Folder 215)
      - "Blue Like Death", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 216)
      - "Browning, Montana", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 217)
      - "Butte, Montana: For No One You Would Know", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 218)
      - "By Candle-Light", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 219)
      - "By Night off Attica", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - "Call to Arms", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - "Candlelight, Poe and Thou" (Box 24, Folder 222)
      - "Carpenter", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - "Childhood in Parts", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 224)
      - "Christmas Comes to Moccasin Flat", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 225)
      - "City Days, Always Tried Happy", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 226)
      - "Clark Fork on Down to Missoula", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 227)
      - "Come Back - All is Forgiven", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 228)
      - "Conspiracy of Rabbits", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 229)
      - "Conversation", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 230)
      - "Conversation with the Wily Fool Hen", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 231)
      - "Counting Clouds", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 232)
      - "Crystal", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 233)
      - "The Damned Yippie", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 234)
      - "Dancing Man", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 235)
      - "Day After Chasing Porcupines", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 236)
      - "The Day the Children Took Over", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 237)
      - "Day to Make up Incompletes", 1968 Aug 14 (Box 24, Folder 238)
      - "Death of a Dog", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 239)
      - "Decision to Step Down", 1968 Mar 31 (Box 24, Folder 240)
      - "Decoy", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 241)
      - "Demise of a Strip Queen", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 242)
      - "Directions to the Nomad", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 243)
      - "Dodson, Montana", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 244)
      - "Downed", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 245)
      - "Dream in Winter", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 246)
      - "Dreaming Winter", 1967 (Box 24, Folder 247)
      - "Dreaming with Others", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 248)
      - "Dream-Work", 1968 Sep 15 (Box 24, Folder 249)
      - "Drinking up on Sarge", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 250)
      - "Drinking Wine", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 251)
      - "Drive for the Dodger", 1968 Sep 24 (Box 24, Folder 252)
      - "Drunk One Night with Gil, the Mexican, Who Can Speak Seven Languages Badly", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 253)
      - "D-Y Bar", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 254)
      - "Eating up the Days", 1968 Jun 30 (Box 24, Folder 255)
      - "Eleven O'Clock Sunday Morning", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 256)
      - "End of May" (Box 24, Folder 257)
      - "Eulynda" (Box 24, Folder 258)
      - "Famine Grew Legs", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 259)
      - "Fantasy Hill", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 260)
      - "Fed up, Fat Gal Thinks of Herself", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 261)
      - "First Spring", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 262)
      - "Flies", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 263)
      - "Flies on the Water", 1967 (Box 24, Folder 264)
      - "For My Brother in Viet Nam", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 265)
      - "Forty Days Siege of Tam Ky", [ca. 1968] (Box 24, Folder 266)
      - "Founded 1827 the Lindenwood Girls" (Box 24, Folder 267)
      - "Frank the Cat Got Worse", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 268)
      - "From the Humdrum", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 269)
      - "Fun", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 270)
      - "Gaining Ground" (Box 24, Folder 271)
      - "Gesture Down to Guatemala", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 272)
      - "Getting Things Straight", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 273)
      - "Going to Remake this World", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 274)
      - "Good News from Section D" (Box 24, Folder 275)
      - "Goodbye, Hello the Whores", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 276)
      - "Goodbye to the Gold Girl", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 277)
      - "Grandfather at the Rest Home", 1968 Jun 5 (Box 24, Folder 278)
      - "Grandma's Man" (Box 24, Folder 279)
      - "Gravely", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 280)
      - "Grief at the Bijou", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 281)
      - "Gus Rock", 1968 Aug 20 (Box 24, Folder 282)
      - "The Happy Birthday", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 283)
      - "Harlem, Montana", [ca. 1966] (Box 24, Folder 284)
      - "Hays Mission and Further Out" (Box 24, Folder 285)
      - "Heading up the Mountain", 1967 (Box 24, Folder 286)
      - "Hiking", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 287)
      - "Hole-in-the-Wall Lodge", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 288)
      - "The Home of Turkey King", [ca. 1966] (Box 25, Folder 289)
      - "Hopeful Elegy for Indian Past" (Box 25, Folder 290)
      - "How Did You Like It?", [ca. 1966] (Box 25, Folder 291)
      - "Hump Shoulders", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 292)
      - "Hungry Horse", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 293)
      - "I Can't Be Poet and Lover Too..." (Box 25, Folder 294)
      - "If Hunters Were Chinese", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 295)
      - "If I Could Dream Like Liberace", 1968 Oct (Box 25, Folder 296)
      - "If the Sun Don't Shine" (Box 25, Folder 297)
      - "In My First Hard Springtime", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 298)
      - "In My Lifetime", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 299)
      - "In the American Express Line", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 300)
      - "Indian Church" (Box 25, Folder 301)
      - "Indian Love Call" (Box 25, Folder 302)
      - "Infatuation with a Sleepy Sorority Girl", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 303)
      - "Janice", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 304)
      - "Lady in a Distant Face", 1968 Dec 9 (Box 25, Folder 305)
      - "Lady Waiting", 1968 Jul 28 (Box 25, Folder 306)
      - "Lament to the Impervious Moon", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 307)
      - "Larger Things", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 308)
      - "The Last Priest Didn't Even Say Goodbye", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 309)
      - "Laughing in the Belly", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 310)
      - "Legends Like This", 1968 Jun 3 (Box 25, Folder 311)
      - "Let Me Define for You", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 312)
      - "Let Me Warn You About Turkeys", 1968 Apr 9 (Box 25, Folder 313)
      - "Letter", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 314)
      - "Life Support System", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 315)
      - "Lines Without Roses", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 316)
      - "Loon Tune", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 317)
      - "Lost Trail Pass", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 318)
      - "Making Friends with the Blackfeet" (Box 25, Folder 319)
      - "The Man From Washington", 1968 Nov 1 (Box 25, Folder 320)
      - "A Man Who Knows His Crows", 1968 Sep 2 (Box 25, Folder 321)
      - "Many White Horses and the Crows" (Box 25, Folder 322)
      - "Marcy", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 323)
      - "Marcy Slows Her Cool (The Priests and the Fox)" (Box 25, Folder 324)
      - "Marcy in the Cave", [ca. 1966] (Box 25, Folder 325)
      - "Marcy in the Mission", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 326)
      - "Marcy's Riddle", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 327)
      - "Masochistic Sunday", [ca. 1966] (Box 25, Folder 328)
      - "May Night Ramble", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 329)
      - "Memory", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 330)
      - "Memory for Real", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 331)
      - "Message from Montana", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 332)
      - "A Mild Complex", 1968 Oct (Box 25, Folder 333)
      - "Mile High Rapist", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 334)
      - "A Minor Coda", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 335)
      - "Missoula Spring, 1968", 1968 Apr 7 (Box 25, Folder 336)
      - "Montana, Nothing Like Boston", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 337)
      - "Mose Carrywater", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 338)
      - "Moving into Spring", 1968 Apr 11 (Box 25, Folder 339)
      - "My Sister, My Lover", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 340)
      - "Mythology of Old Men", 1968 Apr 13 (Box 25, Folder 341)
      - "Names, Colors and Clay" (Box 25, Folder 342)
      - "Never Give a Bum an Even Break", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 343)
      - "Night Hawk", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 344)
      - "Not in North Dakota, You Don't", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 345)
      - "Obsessions for Elaine", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 346)
      - "On a Riotous Night", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 347)
      - "On the Fire Line at Hays", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 348)
      - "On This Gray Day...", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 349)
      - "One for Drinks", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 350)
      - "One More Time", 1968 Aug 9 (Box 25, Folder 351)
      - "The Only Bar in Dixon", 1970 Feb (Box 25, Folder 352)
      - "Passing Through", 1968 Apr 21 (Box 25, Folder 353)
      - "Picnic Weather", 1968 May 26 (Box 26, Folder 354)
      - "Pigeons for Peace", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 355)
      - "Plains Song", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 356)
      - "Plea to Those Who Matter", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 357)
      - "Please Forward", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 358)
      - [Poems by James Welch], n.d. (Box 26, Folder 359)
      - [Poems written in Greece], 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 360)
      - "Poet as Charmer", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 361)
      - "Pools for Lures", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 362)
      - "Prairie View Addition", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 363)
      - "Rained out on Rock Creek", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 364)
      - "Red Shoes and Damp Roses" (Box 26, Folder 365)
      - "The Renegade Wants Words", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 366)
      - "Reno Dawn", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 367)
      - "Riding the Earthboy Forty", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 368)
      - "Rivers Forget the Lovely Mountains", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 369)
      - "Rock Creek", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 370)
      - "A Savior Comes to Campus", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 371)
      - "Sayonara", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 372)
      - "Scissor-Bill", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 373)
      - "Seattle, Way", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 374)
      - "Senator and His Party" (Box 26, Folder 375)
      - "Shrove Monday" (Box 26, Folder 376)
      - "Snow Country Weavers", 1968 Dec 10 (Box 26, Folder 377)
      - "Somnambulance", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 378)
      - "Song for the Season", 1968 Aug 4 (Box 26, Folder 379)
      - "Spring for All Seasons", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 380)
      - "Story Hour", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 381)
      - "Surviving", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 382)
      - "Talking Business with Mose Carrywater", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 383)
      - "Talking Night Again up the Rattlesnake", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 384)
      - "Tan in a Free Season", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 385)
      - "Ten Years Gone, Grandmother" (Box 26, Folder 386)
      - "Thanksgiving at Snake Butte", 1968 Oct (Box 26, Folder 387)
        See also: Correspondence, Lone Goose Press, Box 39, folder 673
      - "There are Limits", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 388)
      - "There are Silent Legends", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 389)
      - "There is a Right Way", 1968 Aug 13 (Box 26, Folder 390)
      - "These are Lonely Mountains", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 391)
      - "These Simple Folk", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 392)
      - "Thinking Wind Across the Great Divide", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 393)
      - "Threads and Needles" (Box 26, Folder 394)
      - "Three Nights Running Mad", 1966 (Box 26, Folder 395)
      - "Three Wishes From the Magic In-Law", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 396)
      - "To a Poet in (Maybe) Guatemala", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 396a)
      - "To the Keeper of the Keys", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 397)
      - "Toward Speech", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 398)
      - "Town", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 399)
      - [Empty folder] (Box 26, Folder 400)
      - "Trestles on the Blackfoot", 1969 Sep 30 (Box 26, Folder 401)
      - "Truth Becomes You", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 402)
      - "TV Eyes", 1968 Oct (Box 26, Folder 403)
      - "Two for the Festival", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 404)
      - "Unmailed Card from Bonneville", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 405)
      - "Up the Canyon with Marcy", 1966 (Box 26, Folder 406)
      - "Vassar", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 407)
      - "Verifying the Dead", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 408)
      - "The Versatile Historian", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 409)
      - "Vision at Michel", 1968 Aug 2 (Box 26, Folder 410)
      - "Visitation", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 411)
      - "Wading with Marcy", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 412)
      - "A Way to Drag the Lochsa", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 413)
      - "Weather Eye", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 414)
      - "Weekend Trip to the Big Hole Country", 1968 May 21 (Box 26, Folder 415)
      - "When the Corn Comes up a Crooked Way", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 416)
      - "When Wine Goes Bad", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 417)
      - "Where Were You?", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 418)
      - "Why I Didn't Go to Delphi", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 419)
      - "Why Me", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 420)
      - "Wine on a Blonde Stream" (Box 27, Folder 421)
      - "Winter Act of Love", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 422)
      - "Winter Face, Believe the Wind" (Box 27, Folder 423)
      - "Winter Indian", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 424)
      - "Wolf Song, The Rain", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 425)
      - "Woman Speaks to Great Bear", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 426)
      - "The World on Top", 1968 Nov 1 (Box 27, Folder 427)
      - "The World's Only Corn Palace", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 428)
      - "The Wrath of Lester Lame Bull", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 429)
      - "You Gone, Martin luther King Dead", 1968 Apr 6 (Box 27, Folder 430)
      - Untitled, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 431-432)
  - SHORT FICTION
    - "Bits of Straw," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 433)
    - "Meeting," draft, typescript, with notes in unidentified hand, 1965 Feb 9 (Box 28, Folder 434)
    - Untitled, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1960s] (Box 28, Folder 435)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - Killing Custer
      - Book proposal, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 436)
      - Background material and notes (Box 28, Folder 437-441)
        Includes electronic files available through Access Services: Disk#15; Last Stand #1 and Disk#11; Jim's Disk
      - Draft, Chapters 1-4, electronic, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 442)
        Available through Access Services: Disk#06; Little Bighorn Book Backup, Chap. 1, 2, 3, 1/2 of 4
      - Draft (incomplete), electronic, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 443)
        Available through Access Services: Disk#27; Little Bighorn book
      - Draft, computer printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 444-445)
      - [Misc. early] drafts, computer printouts, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 446-447)
      - Drafts, computer printouts and computer printout photocopy, corrected (Box 29, Folder 448-449)
      - Draft (incomplete), computer printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 450-451)
      - Drafts, computer printouts, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 452-453)
      - [Misc. chapters] drafts, computer printouts, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 454)
      - Draft, computer printout, corrected by Gerry Howard, photocopy, 1993 Dec 20 (Box 30, Folder 455-456)
      - Final Draft, computer printout, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 457-458)
      - Drafts, computer printouts, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 459)
      - Comments from unidentified reader, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 460)
      - Draft, electronic, 1993-1994 (Box 31, Folder 461)
        Available through Access Services: Disk#08; Killing Custer, Complete
      - Draft, computer printout, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations (Box 31, Folder 462-463)
      - Proof, Master Set, 1st Pass, 1994 Apr 14 (Box 31, Folder 464-465)
      - Proof, Master Set, 1st Pass, photocopy, 1994 Apr 13 (Box 31, Folder 466-467)
      - Proof, Master Set, 2nd Pass, 1994 Jun 10 (Box 32, Folder 468-469)
      - Proof, Master Set, Confirmation, 1994 Jun 27 (Box 32, Folder 470-471)
      - Proofs, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 472)
      - Press kit, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 473)
      - Film project notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 474)
- Writings of Others, 1982-2006; Series II; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Series II, Writings of Others, is arranged into two subseries: Writings of Others on James Welch and Other Writings.
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS ON JAMES WELCH
    - Articles, 1982-2006 (Box 33, Folder 475-482)
    - Books and theses, 1986, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 483-484)
    - Books and theses, 1998-2000 (Box 34, Folder 485-486)
    - Interviews, 2000-2001 (Box 34, Folder 487-488)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - Other writings, 1991-1992, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 489-490)
- Correspondence, 1962-2002; Series III; 4.38; (11 boxes)
  Series II, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - "A" General, 1975-1999 (Box 35, Folder 491-492)
    Includes photographs of Welch and unidentified others
  - Adams, James R., 1944-, 1998 Dec 2 (Box 35, Folder 493)
  - The Agora, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 494)
  - Albin Michel (Firm), 1991-2002, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 495)
    Includes copy of third-party letter from firm to University of Montana
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 2001 Sep 4 (Box 35, Folder 496)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1998 Nov 1 (Box 35, Folder 497)
  - American Association of University Women, 1995 Jan 13 (Box 35, Folder 498)
  - American Audio Prose Library, 1985-1993 (Box 35, Folder 499)
  - American Center of P.E.N., 1994-1997 (Box 35, Folder 500)
  - American Indian Higher Education Consortium (Box 35, Folder 501)
  - Anchor Books, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 502)
  - Arizona Daily Wildcat, 1992 Aug 11 (Box 35, Folder 503)
  - Arnett, Carroll, 1993 Feb 26 (Box 35, Folder 504)
  - Associated Press, 1997 Jul 7 (Box 35, Folder 505)
  - Associated Writing Programs, 1992-1997 (Box 35, Folder 506)
  - Association of Departments of English, 1999 (Box 35, Folder 507)
  - "B" General, 1990-2002, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 508-511)
  - Balakian, Peter, 1995 Mar 29 (Box 35, Folder 512)
  - Bambace, Anthony, 1997 Jun 7 (Box 35, Folder 513)
  - Bantam Books (Firm), 1977 Jul 15 (Box 35, Folder 514)
  - Barnes, Kim, 1991 Dec 10 (Box 35, Folder 515)
    Includes copies of poems by Barnes
  - Bataille, Gretchen M., 1997 (Box 35, Folder 516)
  - Baucus, Max, 2000 Feb 11 (Box 35, Folder 517)
  - Bear Claw, Dean Curtis, 1997-2000 (Box 35, Folder 518)
  - Bednarik, Joseph S., 1996 Feb 22 (Box 35, Folder 519)
  - Beer, Ralph, 2000 Oct 5 (Box 35, Folder 520)
  - Bellinelli, Matteo, 1992 Feb 28 (Box 35, Folder 521)
  - Biagiotti, Cinzia, 1989 Jul 10 (Box 36, Folder 522)
  - Bickley, Lynn [S.?], 1992 (Box 36, Folder 523)
  - Big Sky Journal, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 524)
    Includes printout of article by Welch entitled "Dana Boussard"
  - Blaustein, Arthur I., 1992 Jun 30 (Box 36, Folder 525)
  - The Bloomsbury Review, 1991 Aug 27 (Box 36, Folder 526)
  - Blue, Janice, 1987 Feb 9 (Box 36, Folder 527)
  - Blue Heron Press, 1996 Feb 5 (Box 36, Folder 528)
  - Brenner, Gerry, 1996 Oct (Box 36, Folder 528a)
    Includes third-party letters by Annie Dillard, Peter Matthiessen, James Tate, and others in support of Welch's candidacy for an honorary degree
  - Britto, Silvester J., 1999 Mar 10 (Box 36, Folder 529)
  - Brokaw, Tom, 1976-1992, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 530)
  - Bruccoli Clark Layman, Inc., 2001 Nov 26 (Box 36, Folder 531)
    Includes proof of entry on Welch for the Dictionary of Literary Biography
  - Bunge, Nancy L., 1994 Nov 1 (Box 36, Folder 532)
  - Burns, Conrad, 2001 May 11 (Box 36, Folder 533)
  - Busch, Frederick, 1997-1998 (Box 36, Folder 534)
  - Butala, Sharon, 1994 Jul 11 (Box 36, Folder 535)
  - Butler University, 1987 Jun 8 (Box 36, Folder 536)
  - Byer, Kathryn [Stripling], 1996-1997 (Box 36, Folder 537)
  - "C" General, 1975-2001, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 538-541)
    Includes photographs of Hélène Cardona
  - California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 542)
  - Callaloo, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 543)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1995 May 22 (Box 36, Folder 544)
  - Carlile, Henry, 1974 Sep 16 (Box 36, Folder 545)
  - Carroll, Paul, 1967 Sep 6 (Box 36, Folder 546)
  - Center for the Rocky Mountain West, 1993-1996 (Box 36, Folder 547)
  - Centre national du livre (France), 1996 (Box 36, Folder 548)
  - Chicago Humanities Festival, 1999, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 549)
  - Clark, LaVerne Harrell, 1992 Apr 15 (Box 36, Folder 550)
    Includes photographs of Welch by L.H. Clark
  - Clark, Patricia, 1951-, 1997 May 27 (Box 36, Folder 551)
  - Clark, Robert, 1995 Feb 15 (Box 36, Folder 552)
  - Clow, Deborah, 1992 May 12 (Box 36, Folder 553)
  - Colgate University, 1993 Jun 25 (Box 36, Folder 554)
  - Colorado College, 1997-1999 (Box 36, Folder 555)
    Includes photographs of Welch
  - Colorado Council on the Arts and Humanities, 1993 Feb 8 (Box 36, Folder 556)
  - Coltelli, Laura, 1998 Sep 7 (Box 36, Folder 557)
  - Committee for Indian Law Students, 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 558)
  - Comstock, Rolland, 1993-1994 (Box 36, Folder 559)
  - Condon, Phil, 1993 Sep 21 (Box 36, Folder 560)
  - Confederated Salish & Kootenai Tribes of the Flathead Reservation, Montana, 1992 Apr 16 (Box 36, Folder 561)
  - Contemporary Authors, 1995 May 2 (Box 36, Folder 562)
  - Copper Canyon Press, 1999 Jan 22 (Box 37, Folder 563)
  - Cornell University, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 564)
  - Cortese, Guiseppina, 1975 Sep 19 (Box 37, Folder 565)
  - Crowell, Marnie Reed, 1993 Nov 23 (Box 37, Folder 566)
  - Crown Publishers, 1995 Feb 27 (Box 37, Folder 567)
  - Crump, Kathy, 1993 Nov 17 (Box 37, Folder 568)
  - "D" General, 1991-1999, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 569-570)
  - D'Arcy McNickle Center for the American Indian, 1988 Oct 1 (Box 37, Folder 571)
  - DeFrees, Madeline, 1995 Mar 5 (Box 37, Folder 572)
  - Delle Fave, Antonella, 1999 Apr 6 (Box 37, Folder 573)
  - DeMarinis, Rick, 1934-, 1980-1999 (Box 37, Folder 574)
  - DePaul University, 1993 Dec 20 (Box 37, Folder 575)
  - [Diers], Jim, 1998 Feb 26 (Box 37, Folder 576)
  - Dillard, Annie, 1995-1997 (Box 37, Folder 577)
    See also: Brenner, Gerry, Box 36, folder 528a
  - Dorris, Michael, 1993 Dec 20 (Box 37, Folder 578)
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 2000 (Box 37, Folder 579)
  - Dougall, Lucy, 2000 Feb 11 (Box 37, Folder 580)
  - Dragone, Francesca Bandel, 1995-1996 (Box 37, Folder 581)
    Includes draft of Dragone's "Translator's Note" to Fool's Crow
  - Dufresne, John, 1992 May 27 (Box 37, Folder 582)
  - "E" General, 1989-1996 (Box 37, Folder 583)
  - Eastern Montana College, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 584)
  - Eastern Washington University, 2000 Jun 30 (Box 37, Folder 585)
  - Editions Hoebecke, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 586)
  - Elaine Markson Literary Agency, 1974-2001, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 587-589)
    Includes contract and royalty statements
  - Etonnants Voyageurs, 1992-2001 (Box 37, Folder 590)
  - "F" General, 1969-2000 (Box 37, Folder 591)
  - Falaise, Pierre, 1994-1996 (Box 37, Folder 592)
  - Felken, Detlef, 1992 Jul 7 (Box 37, Folder 593)
  - Fete de l'Humanite, 1992-1993 (Box 37, Folder 594)
  - Findlay, John M., 1955-, 2001 May 21 (Box 37, Folder 595)
  - Fiorentino, Daniele, 1957-, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 596)
  - Fitz, Karsten, 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 597)